SHANAKA RUSITH

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Berlin, 13347

PHONE

+4915213994016

EMAIL

rusith@mail.com

LINKS

rusith.me

Github

LinkedIn

GOOD AT

Node JS

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

MongoDB

.Net

C#

LANGUAGES

English - Proficient

Sinhalese - Native

HOBBIES

Reading, Movies

PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer with nearly 7 years of industry experience. A self-taught programmer who started learning to program at age 16. I have learned and worked with a large array of web technologies both back-end and front-end, In organisations both large and small. My experience spans the full gamut of software engineering including web and other technologies which makes me a valuable asset to any software development company looking for someone who can get in and do anything!

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer, arive GmbH

Berlin

Oct 2021 - Present

Helped to design, develop the ARIVE app, a quick-commerce app based in Berlin and Paris.

- Worked in the order and payment teams and made significant contributions in designing and developing features for both back-end APIs, front-end applications (Webshop)
- Owned the payment implementations (full-stack) and was able to successfully integrate with new payment partners. Got the experience working with payment providers such as Stripe, Adyen, PayPal.

Technologies: TypeScript, NodeJS, React, MongoDB, NextJS

Senior Software Engineer, Calcey Technologies

Colombo

Jan 2021 - Sep 2021

At Calcey, I worked in multiple projects including using various technology stacks, including .Net technologies, JS technologies and helped multiple teams at Calcey for multiple projects.

Technologies: .Net(C#), React, MSSQL, MySQL, NodeJS, Angular

Software Engineer, Calcey Technologies

Colombo

Aug 2018 - Jan 2021

Got the opportunity to work on multiple project ranging from Nelly - which is Swedish fashion retailer and multiple projects for BI and machine learning.

Technologies: .Net(C#), React, MSSQL, MySQL, NodeJS, Angular, Python, PowerBI, Talend etc

Jul 2016 - Jan 2021

My roles were to design and develop software for enterprise systems, The main technologies used were C#, .Net, SQL Server, TypeScript, JavaScript and Angular Gained a lot of exposure to other technologies as well such as mobile development.

Technologies: .Net, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, NodeJS, React, Angular, PHP

Trainee Software Engineer, Bourke Technologies

Colombo

Feb 2016 - Jul 2016

During the training period, I learned the basics of software engineering and a lot of technologies and programming languages. Used .Net and JavaScript for most of the projects. Projects covered the apparel industry and service desk software.

Technologies: .Net, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, NodeJS, React, Angular,PHP

OTHER PROJECTS

Pretzel.space

Pretzel (<u>App</u>) is a workspace app with integrated AI and a lot of other tools and capabilities such as task management, document editing, a document cloud. Designed the codebase from the ground up. then continued the project with help of other developers. This project is in active development. I could architect this complex project and maintain a clean, productive code base. I handle the releases for Pretzel. I manage all release pipelines and the cloud architecture on AWS.

Technologies: NodeJS, React, Apollo, Express, NextJS, MySQL. Most of the components are built using TypeScript

ShopShare.tv

<u>ShopShare</u> is a video shopping platform built to help shopping easier by providing help from shopping and fashion experts. I helped to build the project from the ground up. and created the initial, complete version of the Chrome extension which the stylists use to record videos. And built the backend and some core UI components such as the Shopcast file management page. For this project we used NodeJS, React, GraphQL, MySQL, I got the opportunity to work with AWS in this project. I handled the releases and created the release pipeline for this project while I was working with ShopShare.

OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

Genius

<u>Genius</u> is a cross-platform clipboard manager created using the QT library. This was a great learning experience to learn C++. I still use it and it has been very useful for so many people.

Genie

<u>Genie</u> was a big project for me. Genie is a code generation tool that can generate a complete data access layer for .Net projects. The aim was to support all major database systems.

Gimbli

<u>Genie</u> was a big project for me. Genie is a code generation tool that can generate a complete data access layer for .Net projects. The aim was to support all major database systems.

GS Tag Editor

GS Tag Editor This is a desktop application I created to edit media tags on my media files. Used Windows Presentation Foundation to create the UI.

EDUCATION

Secondary Education, St Thomas College

Matale

Jan 2007 - Dec 2015

Secondary education until ALs

Secondary Education, St Thomas College

Colombo

Jan 2016

BCS - PGD in IT - UG